（キラービー）でかした　ヤマト。
Good job, Yamato.
（ヤマト）いや　僕の力では…。
No, that wasn't me.
ナルト自身の力で
止まったようです。
Naruto stopped it all by himself.
しかし　こんな状態のままで
大丈夫なんでしょうか？
But is it okay to
leave things like this?
う～ん。
現在ナルトは　九尾と対決。
Right now, Naruto and
Nine Tails are in a confrontation…
It better be settled soon. We want it
to meet our hopeful expectations!
早めの決着　みんなが待望。
待ってる俺たちとっても退屈。
All this waiting is so drawn out!
To pass the time,
why don't we work out?
退屈しのぎに２人で体操。
こんなときに
ラップかましてる場合ですか！
This isn't the time to be rapping!
シャラップ！
Shuddup!
今　ナルトは己自身のなかで
一人　九尾と戦ってる。
Right now, Naruto is locked in
an internal battle with Nine Tails.
俺たちが
手助けできるのは　ここまでだ。
We cannot help him any further.
If you really care about
Naruto's wellbeing,
ナルトのことを
思っているのであれば→
今　俺たちに
できることは　ただひとつ。
all we can do now…
ナルトを信じて
待っててやることだけだ。
is to have faith in him and wait.
((クシナ：愛してる))
I love you.
《ナルト：何だろう…。
What is this?
すげえ安心する》
I feel so calm…
((クシナ：あなたを愛してる))
I love you.
《すげえ嬉しい》
I feel so happy.
うお～っ！
Damn you, Kushina!
《九尾：クシナめ》
うお～っ！
フフッ。
こ　これは…。
What is this?
いい感じ　このまま監視。
This is real nice!
For now,
keeping watch will suffice!
九尾をおさえている
私のチャクラもそうもたない。
My chakra that's suppressing
the Nine Tails won't last much longer!
今のうちに　やっちゃいなさい！
This is your chance to do it!
おう！
All right!
多重影分身の術！
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
You brat!
ガキ！
いくぜ！
やっぱり強いわね。
Just as I thought.
He's really strong!
食らえ！
Take this!
螺旋超多連丸！
Rasengan Super Barrage!
のぼせるな！
Don't underestimate me!
《まだ　いけるってばね！》
I can keep going, ya know!
ここだ。
Here!
That's…
これは…。
仙人モード。
Sage Mode!
♪～
仙法　超大玉！
Sage Art!
Massive…
螺旋多連丸！
Rasengan Barrage!
もうひと押し！
One more round!
《何だ　この力は…》
What kind of power is this?
引け！
Pull!
うっ…　飛んでけ！
Get out!
《クシナ：やった　九尾のチャクラを
引きずり出したね！》
You did it! You pulled
the Nine Tails' chakra out!
♪～
ん…　んっ？
これは…　これが九尾の…。
This is…
This is the Nine Tails'…
ナルト　わしを…　わしを怒らせたな！
Naruto…
You…
You have infuriated me, Naruto!
ナルト！！
まだ　こんだけの力が！
You still have that much power…
やっぱ　すげぇや　オメエは！
You really are amazing.
《これは　六道の…》
This is the Six Paths…?!
覚えていろ　ナルト。
You watch out, Naruto.
《ごめんな　九尾。
I'm sorry…Nine Tails.
でも　オメエを
悪いようにはしねえから。
But I'll make it up to you.
少しの間　待っててくれ》
So just hang in there
for a little while.
やったわね　ナルト！
You did it, Naruto!
うん…。
Yeah.
母ちゃんは　今…。
Ma, where are you going now?
これで　ミナトのところへ
やっと行ける。
I can finally go and join Minato.
行く前に→
There's something
I must tell you before I go.
あなたに言っておかなきゃ
ならないことがあるの。
ナルト　あなたが生まれた
１６年前の事件。
Naruto…
It's about when you were born
16 years ago.
その真相を言っておくわ。
I'll tell you what really happened.
１６年前の真相？
What really happened…
16 years ago?
私は
あなたの前任の九尾の人柱力。
I was the Nine Tails' Jinchuriki
before you.
まずは　そこからね。
Let's start from there.
Target: Nine Tails
九尾の人柱力だった？
母ちゃんが？
You were
the Nine Tails' Jinchuriki, Ma?
そう。
Yes.
１６年前の話をするには→
Before I can tell you
what happened 16 years ago,
まず私のことについて
知っておいてほしいの。
I need to tell you more
about me.
私は　２番目の九尾の人柱力として
選ばれた。
I was chosen as the second
Jinchuriki host of Nine Tails.
ホント言うと
九尾の人柱力となるため→
Truth be told, I was brought here for
the express purpose
木ノ葉に連れてこられたの。
of being the Nine Tails' Jinchuriki…
LAND OF FIRE        LAND OF EDDIES
from the Land of Eddies.
渦の国からね。
なんで…。
Why?
Why did they have to choose
someone from another land?!
なんで他の国の母ちゃんが→
人柱力なんかになんなきゃ
いけなかったんだよ！？
確かに他の国　他の里だけど→
You're right. I'm from
a different land, and village.
火の国と渦の国　木ノ葉隠れの里と
渦潮隠れの里は→
But the Land of Fire and
the Land of Eddies,
as well as Hidden Leaf Village
and Hidden Eddy Village,
深い関係にあったの。
share a deep bond.
木ノ葉の千手一族と
渦潮のうずまき一族は→
The shinobi of the Senju Clan
of the Hidden Leaf
and the shinobi of the Uzumaki Clan
of the Hidden Eddy
遠い血縁関係にあたる忍たち。
were distant blood relatives.
Our people lived long.
生命力に長けた者ばかりで→
渦潮の里は
別命　長寿の里と呼ばれ…。
So the Hidden Eddy Village was
also known as the Village of Longevity.
封印術を得意とする一族たちが
住んでいたの。
And we specialized in Sealing Jutsu.
ちょっと荒っぽいけどね。
We were also a rowdy bunch.
あなたのお腹の四象封印も
ベースなっているのは→
The Tetragram Seal on
your abdomen is based
もともと私たちの里の術だし→
on a jutsu from our village.
ミナト…　父さんに
いろいろ封印術を教えたのは→
And Minato, your father, learned
various Sealing Jutsu from my mother.
お母さんなのよ。
ナルト　あなたの背中にあるマーク。
Naruto, the symbol on your back…
それが　渦潮隠れのマーク。
That is the symbol
of the Hidden Eddy.
今でも　木ノ葉のなかでは
友好の証しとして→
Even today in Hidden Leaf Village
that symbol is a symbol
of friendship, isn't it?
そのマークが用いられているでしょ？
渦潮隠れの里って…。
So the Hidden Eddy Village…?
今では　もう
なくなってしまった里なの。
It no longer exists.
戦乱の時代
その封印の能力を恐れられ→
During the era of war,
our sealing jutsu abilities
were greatly feared,
狙われて
いつしか滅びてしまった。
so the village was targeted
and destroyed.
Those who survived feared
for their safety,
生き残った者たちも
身分を隠して→
so they hid their identities and
scattered throughout the region.
各地へ
散らばってしまったらしいわ。
だからって　なんで
母ちゃんが　そんなことを…。
Still…why were you chosen?!
渦潮の里のなかでも　私は　特に→
It seems that even
among the Hidden Eddy,
I was born with powerful chakra
able to suppress the Nine Tails.
九尾を抑えこめる強いチャクラを
持って生まれたらしくてね。
初代火影…　千手柱間様と
うちはマダラの戦いは知ってる？
Do you know about the battle…
between the First Hokage,
Hashirama Senju, and Madara Uchiha?
うん。
Uh-huh…
私の前任の人柱力だった人は
初代火影の妻になった人。
The Jinchuriki before me
was the woman
who became the wife of
the First Hokage.
その人の名は　うずまきミト。
Her name was Mito Uzumaki.
マダラとの戦いで九尾を手にした
初代　柱間様の力になるため→
In order to help Lord First Hokage
who had obtained the Nine Tails
in his battle with Madara,
ミト様は　封印術で
おのれの中に九尾を封印し→
Lady Mito sealed the Nine Tails
inside her body
with a Sealing Jutsu and
became its Jinchuriki.
九尾の人柱力となった。
それからは　ずっと
木ノ葉が　九尾を所有してきた。
From then on,
the Hidden Leaf maintained
possession of the Nine Tails.
でも　そのミト様が
余命わずかになったとき→
But when Lady Mito's days
were coming to an end,
私が連れてこられたの。
I was brought to Hidden Leaf
as the vessel for the Nine Tails.
九尾の器としてね。
それじゃ　まるで
もの扱いじゃねえかよ！
You were just being used!
連れてこられたとき　私にも
事実は知らされていなかったし→
When I was first brought to the village,
I wasn't told a thing.
それを聞いたときは
ショックだったのは　たしか。
It was quite a shock
when I was told why I was there.
このことは　すべて
極秘とされていたし→
This was a closely guarded secret.
And the only ones who knew
知っていたのは
三代目を含め　上層部　数人だけ。
were the Third Hokage and
a few of the top officials.
三忍ですら知らされていなかった。
Not even the Legendary Sannin
were told about this.
私は　人柱力のプレッシャーや孤独感で
押し潰されそうになった。
I was nearly overwhelmed by
the pressure of being the Jinchuriki
and the loneliness I felt.
でも　前任のミト様が
私を呼んでくれて…。
But Lady Mito, the previous Jinchuriki,
summoned me…
((ミト：もそっと近くに。
Come closer.
♪～
私も　お前も
九尾の器として　ここへ来た。
Like you, I was brought here
to become the vessel
for the Nine Tails.
そのことを聞いたときは
驚いたであろう。
I can imagine your shock
when you learned of this.
悲しかったであろう。
苦しんだであろう。
How sad you must have been.
How you have suffered.
私には　本当のことを
言っていいんですよ。
You can tell me the truth.
はい…。
Yes…
いいですか？
確かに　私たちは九尾の器です。
Now listen carefully.
Indeed, we are the vessels
for the Nine Tails.
でもね　たとえ　人柱力として
生きていくことになっても→
However, there is a way
to find happiness
幸せでいられる方法は　あるのよ。
even if you must live as a Jinchuriki.
(まず　先に　その器に…))
First…
by filling ourselves.
その器に愛を見つけて入れなさい。
By filling myself with love first,
そうすれば
たとえ　九尾の人柱力として→
I would be able to
live a happy life
生きていくことになっても
幸せでいられるって。
despite being
the Nine Tails' Jinchuriki.
ミト様は　そう教えてくださったの。
なら　母ちゃんは→
That is what Lady Mito taught me.
So you were happy even if
you were the Jinchuriki, Ma?
人柱力だったけど幸せだった？
うん。
Yes.
もう　ナルト…
アンタが泣くことないじゃない。
Naruto… Now why are you crying?
あれ？
何？
Wait…
What is it?
１６年前に木ノ葉を襲った
九尾の事件…。
That time 16 years ago
when the Nine Tails attacked
Hidden Leaf Village…
あれは　暁の面をしている男の
仕業だったって→
Dad said a man wearing
an Akatsuki mask was behind it.
父ちゃんが言ってた。
それなのに　なんで
母ちゃんが九尾を持ってたんだ？
So how come you had
the Nine Tails, Mom?
父さんから
詳しくは聞かされてないようね。
I see that your father didn't
tell you all the details.
それもそうかも…。
Of course.
あのとき　私のほうの割合を大きく
ミナトのほうは時間がなかったのね。
Back then,
there was so much going on
and Minato didn't have much time.
たしかに　そう。
It's true. The fact is that,
16 years ago,
１６年前　里を襲った九尾は
その面の男が操ったのは事実。
a masked man was manipulating
the Nine Tails that
attacked the village.
でも　その寸前までは→
But moments earlier,
私が九尾を封印して
持っていたの。
I had the Nine Tails sealed
and in my possession.
じゃあ　なんで？
Then why?
その面の男…　ソイツは　なぜだかは
わからないけど　知ってたの。
That masked man.
I don't know how,
but that masked man knew…
何を？
Knew what?
人柱力の尾獣の封印が弱まる
唯一の機会を知っていた。
He knew about the one chance
he had to weaken the seal,
which kept the Tailed Beast
locked inside the Jinchuriki.
そこを狙われて　九尾を奪われた。
He waited for that moment
to steal the Nine Tails.
封印が弱まる　唯一の機会！？
The one chance to weaken the seal?!
なんだってばよ　それ！
What was it?
出産よ。
It was childbirth.
人柱力の女性が妊娠をし
出産を迎えるまでの　約１０か月間→
During the approximately
ten months from the time
a female Jinchuriki gets pregnant
and gives birth,
封印に使ってるエネルギーが→
the Tailed Beast Seal
weakens proportionally
お腹の子供へと
移行していくために→
as the energy normally
used to maintain the seal
尾獣の封印が　それに比例して
弱まっていく傾向にあるの。
is diverted to the growing baby.
それじゃあ…。
Then…
今より１６年前…　１０月１０日。
Sixteen years ago…on October 10…
HIDDEN LEAF HOSPITAL
((おめでとう。
Congratulations!
え？
What?
予定日は…　そう　１０月１０日。
Your due date is October 10!
Oh then…yeah!
だってばね！
（ミナト）えっ　赤ちゃんが？
Huh? A baby?
私　母親になるんだってばね。
I'm going to be a mother, ya know!
俺が…　父親になる…。
And I'm going be a father.
母親だってばね！
A mother, ya know!
父親になるんだ！
I'm going to be a father!
母親だってばね！
A mother, ya know!
フフ…。
これで　俺も父親か！
Imagine that,
I'm going to be a father!
♪～
クシナ　出産に際し→
Kushina, there is something
I must explain to you
お前に説明しておかなければ
ならぬことがある。
about giving birth.
前任のミト様が　そうだった。
It happened to Lady Mito,
the previous Jinchuriki, too.
出産のとき　九尾の封印が
解けそうになったのじゃ。
During her labor,
the Nine Tails' seal was nearly broken.
もしものことを考え　すまぬが→
I'm sorry,
but as a precautionary measure,
we're going to ask you
to deliver the child
里から少し離れた結界の中で
出産してもらうことになった。
somewhere away from the village,
inside a barrier.
封印のこともあるし
出産には　僕も立ち会うよ。
We have the seal to think of,
so I will be accompanying you.
ミナトと暗部のタジ　そして
わしの妻　ビワコを付き添わせる。
Minato and Taji from
the Anbu Black Ops.
Also I will send my wife, Biwako,
to be with you.
これも　すべて極秘とする。
This is to be done in utmost secrecy.
もちろん　護衛もつけるが
すべて　わし直轄の暗部じゃ。
Naturally, I will assign bodyguards,
but they will be Anbu Black Ops
under my direct orders.
先に行って　準備しておくから。
I'll go on ahead and
prepare everything.
うん。
All right.
場所までは
あちしが案内する。
I will take you there.
クシナ！
あ…　はい。
Kushina!
Oh, yes.
ありがとうございます。
I appreciate it.
そろそろ　移動しておくえ。
はい。
We should go soon.
Yes.
あら。
Oh!
うわぁ…。
Oh my…
女の子だっけ？
フフ…　男の子よ。
Was it a girl?
It's a boy.
かわいい。
So cute…
なんて　お名前でちゅか？
What's your name?
サスケよ。
It's Sasuke.
おぉ…　三代目の父上と
おんなじ名前かえ。
Oh, so he was named after
father of the Third Hokage!
はい。
強い　立派な忍になるように　と。
Yes, so that he will grow up
to be a strong and fine shinobi.
クシナのところも　もうすぐでしょ？
You will be giving birth
soon too, right, Kushina?
名前は
先に決めといたほうがいいわよ。
You should pick a name
in advance.
もう　決めてあるの。
I already have.
名前は　ナルト。
His name will be Naruto.
サスケ君とは同期になるから
仲よくしてくだちゃいね。
You'll be classmates, Sasuke,
so be friends, okay?
ところでさ…　やっぱり痛いの？
By the way, does it really hurt?
へぇ…　クシナでも怖いことあるんだ。
意外。
So there's actually something
that scares you, Kushina!
I'm surprised!
ほら　行くぞえ　クシナ。
Let's go, Kushina!
あ…　はい。
またね。
Oh, yes!
See you again!
一応　お前の出産行事は
極秘じゃえ。
The details of your birthing
are supposed to be top secret.
移動までの間　知り合いがいても
接触は　なるべく避けるのじゃ。
Until we get to our location,
you must avoid any contact,
even with your friends.
はい　すみません。
Yes, I'm sorry.
それからじゃ…
里から離れるといっても→
Also, we are leaving
the village secretly.
極秘事項。　陣痛がきても
あまり大声を出すでないぞえ。
If your labor pains begin,
try not to cry out loud!
は…　はい。
Oh…right.
（クシナ）あ～っ！　痛いってばね～！！
It hurts, ya know!
うぅ～っ！
あの…　こんな大声で痛がるクシナを
初めて見たのですが→
BIND
I've never seen Kushina
in so much pain.
これは　大丈夫なんでしょうか？
Is she…all right?
大丈夫じゃえ。　それより　お前は
九尾の封印をちゃんと見とれ。
She's all right!
Never mind that.
Just stay focused
on the Nine Tail's seal!
うぅ…　あ～っ！
しかし　これは…。
But she's…
四代目火影ともあろうもんが
おたおたすなえ！
You are the Fourth Hokage!
Act like one!
男なら　痛さで
とうに　くたばっとる。
A man would have dropped dead
from such pain long ago.
じゃが　女は強い！
But women are strong!
《強い…。
九尾が出ようともがいている。
He's so strong!
The Nine Tails is struggling
to get out!
頑張れ　クシナ！》
Hang in there, Kushina!
頑張れ　ナルト！
Hang in there, Naruto!
♪～
うぅ～っ！
頭は出た。　もう少しじゃえ　クシナ。
I can see his head!
You're almost there, Kushina!
頑張って　クシナさん！
Hang on, Kushina!
グオォーッ！
ナルト！　早く出てこい！
Naruto! Come out quickly!
九尾は出てくるな！
Nine Tails, you stay put!
うぅ～っ！
(お湯じゃ！
はい！))
Hot water!
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
お楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手→